[{"question":"18. The appearance of albumin in the urine is most likely due to: ","a":"(a) increase in the blood pressure. ","b":"(b) decrease in the blood osmotic corpuscles. ","c":"(c) damage to the Malpighian corpuscles.","d":" (d) damage to the proximal convoluted tubules.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"2.  A man takes large amount of protein. He is likely to excrete more amount of: ","a":"(a) Water","b":"(b) Glucose id ","c":"(c) Urea and uric acid ","d":" (d) Salts","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"3. Aquatic reptiles are: ","a":"(a) Ammonotelic ","b":"(b) Ureotelic over land","c":"(c) Ureotelic","d":"(d) Ureotelic in water","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"4.  In mammalian kidneys, Bowman's capsules or Malpighian corpuscles occur in:","a":"(a) Cortex ","b":"(b) Medulla ","c":" (c) Pelvis","d":"(d) All of these","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"5.  Reabsorption of chloride ions from glomerular filtrate in kidney tubule occurs by:","a":"(a) Active transport ","b":" (b) Diffusion","c":"(c) Osmosis ","d":" (d) Brownian movement","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"6. Synthesis of urea in liver takes place by:  ","a":"(a) Nitrogen cycle ","b":"(b) Kreb's cycle ","c":" (e) Ornithine cycle","d":"(d) Glycolysis","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"7. Uric acid gets deposited in small joints to produce:","a":"(a) Rheumatoid arthritis. ","b":"(b) Gout","c":"(c) Osteoarthritis ","d":" (d) All of the above","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"8. Diabetes insipidus is a condition in which a person is unable to produce sufficient levels of the hormone ADH. The hormone increases the permeability of water of the second (distal) convoluted tubule and collecting duct in the kidney nephrons. What is produced as a result?  ","a":"(a) Large volumes of concentrated urine ","b":"(b) Large volumes of dilute urine","c":"(c) Small volumes of concentrated urine ","d":" (d) Small volumes of dilute urine","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"9.  The loops of Henle in the kidneys of a desert kangaroo rat are much longer than those in a white laboratory rat because the:","a":"(a) kangaroo rat lives in an environment where water is scarce.","b":"(b) white rat's diet is much less varied than the kangaroo rat's.","c":"(c) kangaroo rat cannot always find food. ","d":"(d) kangaroo rat produces more body wastes.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"10. Blood plasma contains proteins but glomerular filtrate does not. Why does this difference in composition occur?","a":"(a) Blood osmotic pressure is maintained by the presence of plasma proteins..","b":"(b) Proteins are actively transported from the kidney tubule back into the blood capillaries","c":"(c) Proteins cannot pass pass through through the membranes of the glomerular capillaries.","d":"(d) There is a high hydrostatic pressure in the blood within the glomerular capillaries.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"11. In human beings the capsular urine entering the Proximal Convoluted Tubule (PCT) is:","a":"(a) Isotonic to blood ","b":" (b) Hypotonic to blood","c":"(c) Hypertonic to blood ","d":" (d) Isotonic to sea water","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"12. If the diameter of afferent renal arteriole is decreased and that of efferent renal arteriole increased, ultra filtration will:","a":"(a) Be faster ","b":"(b) Be slower","c":"(c) Not take place ","d":"(d) Take place in the same speed","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"13. The voluntary response to the distension of urinary bladder is:","a":"(a) Polyurea ","b":"(b) Micturition ","c":" (c) Mellitus","d":"(d) Menstruation","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"14. Refer the following diagram and identify the parts of a kidney indicated as 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5.","a":"(a) 1 cortex. 2 nephron, 4-medulla, 5-ureter 3 - pelvis,","b":"(b) 1 cortex, 2 medulla. 3 - nephron, 4-pelvis, S - ureter","c":"(c) 1 nephron, 2 cortex, 3 medulla. 4-ureter, 5 pelvis","d":"(d) 1 nephron, 2 cortex, 3 4-pelvis, 5- ureter medulla,","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"15. Match the column-I with column-II and choose the correct option.  Column-I  (Excretory organs)  A.  Nephridia  B. Malpighian tubules  C. Protonephridia  D. Kidneys  Column-II  (Animals)  1.  Hydra  II. Leech  III Shark  IV. Round worms  V. Cockroach","a":"(a) A - II; B - V; C - IV; D - III","b":"(b) A - IV; B - II; C - I; D - V  ","c":"(c) A - V; B - II; C - IV; D - III","d":"(d) A - I * I / B - I * V / C - V / D - I","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"16. If the afferent arteriole that supplies blood to the glomerulus becomes dilated: ","a":"(a) the protein concentration of the filtrate decreases.","b":"(b) hydrostatic pressure in the glomerulus decreases.","c":"(c) the glomerular filtration rate increases.","d":"(d) All of the above","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"17. In which one of the following ways does the blood leaving the glomerulus of mammalian kidney tubulo differ from the blood entering the glomerulus? ","a":"(a) It has a lower concentration of plasma","b":"(b) It contains fewer corpuscles per unit volume,","c":"(c) It has a lower concentration of crystalloids. ","d":" (d) It has a higher concentration of crystalloids.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"18. The appearance of albumin in the urine is most likely due to:","a":"(a) increase in the blood pressure.","b":"(b) decrease in the blood osmotic corpuscles. ","c":"(c) damage to the Malpighian corpuscles. ","d":" (d) damage to the proximal convoluted tubules.","hint":"","correct":"c"}]